What's wrong, Jiro?
Another fight, hun?
Well...
The guys were
makin' fun of me again.
- NACHI
- Said I was some
weirdo animal whisperer.
- That I was "different."
- Oh, sweetie...
- I know it's not easy.
But you know, Jiro...
Being different is actually
a beautiful thing.
- NACHI
- Why?
- It means you have talents
unique only to you.
Well, I don't get it.
You'll understand
one day, I promise!
- #1 THE FUTURE IS IN OUR HANDS
- Hey, you got any idea
who you're messing with?
Our sempai's head
of the Demon League!
We control every inch
of this place!
And why should I care?
You're just a little prick
hiding behind a big prick,
a good-for-nothin' poser.
What did you—?!
You little—!
Damn!
Shit talking punk!
Wh—? He...
Made ya look!
It's called
Utsusemi, got it, jackass?
Now just chill the hell out.
Wh-Who is this freak?
Some kinda ninja!
Now what's wrong?
You both can have a taste,
if you want it that bad.
Pathetic wannabe punks!
The hell you think you are?
Hmph...
Waste of time goons.
Phew, you really saved us!
We owe ya one, Jiro!
They've been
really terrorizing us lately!
At least now
those guys'll leave us alone.
But it's you I'm
worried about, Jiro.
They're gonna be
really mad at you now.
Eh, don't worry!
I'm way used to it now.
It's that look ya give...
You just rub people
the wrong way, Jiro!
Shuddup!
Wanna be yakitori?
Right, catch ya later!
And try to keep
your noses outta the trash, okay?
-See ya!
Dammit!
You've got shit for brains!
Jiro!
You got in another fight,
didn't you?
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
I didn't teach you
the art of the shinobi
so you could
act like some punk!
Shut up!
And what good
is shinobi anyhow?
-You're just a dinosaur—
-Watch your mouth!
Okay, Jiro...
This is the Azuma family heirloom.
Our venerable shinobigatana!
It was the Edo period when
your ancestors received,
from the shogun himself,
this ancient and honorable blade.
Now respect your roots
and act like a true Azuma!
Ungrateful idiot!
Yeah right...
I bet it's a harmless fake.
Fine then.
So you think it is a fake...
See how dull it feels
against your flesh!
Leave me alone!
Sheesh.
The old man really lost it.
Crazy fossil.
Hey, Jiro!
Huh?
Tonight's the
town association meeting.
I won't be back till late.
Now don't forget to lock up.
Shut it, old man!
Hmph...
Don't forget to lock up, my ass.
Who's he think I am,
some elementary school kid?
Hey Jiro!
Who is it now?
Oh, hey, I remember you.
What's up?
A cat's in trouble,
in the woods!
A cat?
Hey, we're you taking me?
There!
He's over there!
Holy...
What the hell happened?
You know him?
No, never seen him.
I think he might still be alive,
but my squawks get no response!
Crap...
The little guy's really hurt.
I gotta do something!
Hey!
Hear me?
-Hey! Hey!
-Who's there?
Who dares call upon me?
Rago...
Oh Black Star of Doom,
devourer of the sun...
Awaken from your slumber,
and lend us your might.
Piss the hell off!
You'll wish you never
disrupted my nap.
I take orders from no one, got it?
I see...
'Tis a pity indeed...
Then here it is where
you shall expire!
Oh! There're those peepers!
You've gotta be thirsty!
You were pretty beat up,
I didn't think you'd make it.
But you're a tough little guy!
I'm Jiro.
And you are?
Come on!
Even strays got names.
I'm dealin' with an idiot.
Like you'd understand
if I told you!
I'm an idiot, eh?
I'll kick that furry little ass!
Hey...
Don't be such a scaredy-cat!
Look, this's your
first conversation with a human.
I know it's a lot to take in.
It's not like I'm gonna eat you!
Come out!
I'm not picking up
any spectral energy.
He's human, no doubt 'bout it.
Then he must be...
No.
Tsk...
That's too bad.
Time for my secret weapon.
You're not prying
me outta here with a crowbar.
Well, that was easy!
You know what they say...
The way to a man's heart is
through his stomach.
Huh?!
Funny, a cat
who thinks he's a man.
I am not a cat!
What do you mean?
The name's Rago.
I'm an immortal...
A mononoke.
A mononoke?
People've got
loads of names for 'em.
All you've gotta know
is they're out there.
Perfect...
I think I can get him to confess.
Most of the time we'll
take human or animal form,
and the world is none the wiser.
And some of us...
live up in the mountains
or deep in the woods in solitude.
Huh...
And?
How'd a mononoke
like you end up like this?
So he isn't bluffing...
He really doesn't have a clue.
What?
That like off limits?
I was attacked...
By another mononoke.
What happened?
Some kind of argument?
I don't remember much about it.
I'd been deep
asleep, and for a long time.
Next thing I knew
I'd been woken up.
The sneaky little bastards
had me surrounded.
They demanded my assistance.
I told 'em I wasn't interested,
to get lost...
Ahh, now I get it...
So then they
ganged up on you.
But why'd you turn 'em down?
They're mononoke like you, right?
'Cause I freakin' hate guys like that...
Parasites acting like big shots,
hiding their weakness
behind the strength of others.
What does it matter anyway?
You're a human, you don't believe
a word I'm saying.
Well, to be honest...
None of it makes much sense to me.
But that doesn't mean
I don't believe you!
Guess you forgot
I can talk to animals!
Why would I freak
out 'bout some mononoke?
You're one helluva weirdo.
Hey, watch it!
Kishimojin
reporting to headquarters...
Chief, do you read me?
Shiba here.
Find anything?
Yes...
I'm at coordinates E-16,
in the woods.
I've found blood.
I'm absolutely certain.
It's Rago's.
I'm picking up
one type of spectral energy,
and it stops right here.
He might still be nearby.
All right.
I'll regroup with the search team.
Pull back for now.
Got it.
Not like I couldn't
handle this on my own...
Woah, crazy!
You're already healed up!
You really are no
ordinary cat, are ya?
I knew it...
You didn't believe a word I said.
Well, half of it.
The rest I thought was just crazy
talk by a cat on death's door.
You little—!
Ah, you know...
This really reminds
me of those times with Nachi.
Nachi?
Yeah, my old dog.
- Yeah, my old dog.
- NACHI
- She was the biggest, fluffiest,
- most caring dog
a guy could ask for.
Come to think of it,
kinda the exact opposite of you.
I'll kill you, punk kid!
Back then,
I got bullied all the time.
I'd come home covered in mud,
cuts, and scrapes.
Nachi'd take one look at me
and ask me to give her a bath.
She'd say, "you scrub my fur,
and I'll make sure
all the yuckiness from your day
goes down the drain, too."
Then she'd always say,
"I'm so lucky to have you, Jiro."
"Who else gets to have their owner
bathe them whenever they want?"
"You've got the gift of helping."
"Make sure you share
that gift with others too."
"It's your unique gift," she'd say.
-Hey...
-Okay, time to rinse!
I'm sorry, kid.
I really owe you one.
But I've gotta go.
So long.
Damn...
My wounds've healed,
but my strength isn't
what it used to be.
I've gotta get away
from this place.
Hey, looking a little
unsteady there.
Hey, when did you...?
Wanna keep it down?
It's the middle of the night.
But you were sound asleep!
That was my Kawarimi.
What? Of all the cheap tricks...
Forget that...
Where do you think
you're going in that condition?
Where I go is none of your concern.
None of my concern?
Remember, I'm the one
who saved your life!
I don't remember
asking you for any help.
Whadja just say?
You helped me
because you wanted to,
so you can cut the savior act.
Besides, I would've been just fine
with dying back there.
Huh?
What's that
supposed to mean?
Like I said,
it's none of your business.
All right,
you can cut it out now, okay!
I don't know what your story is,
but don't ever
talk 'bout dying like—
You don't know when to shut up.
Keep yammering,
and I'll turn your windpipe
into my personal
scratching post, kid.
I know your memory's
not that short.
I'm a mononoke!
A human-eating specter!
You and I come from
completely different worlds!
Do me a favor,
and leave me the hell alone!
Looks like you two are
enjoying yourselves.
Mind if I join ya?
You don't mind...
Right, Rago?
Crap...
They're after me already.
Hey, douchebag!
You always turn up at people's
houses uninvited?
Look, I don't know who you are,
but I'm pretty pissed off right now.
That means piss off.
Heh! Relax, human.
I'll devour you in no time!
Not so fast!
You and I come from
completely different worlds!
Do me a favor,
and leave me the hell alone!
What's wrong?
It's almost like
you want me to catch you!
You bastard!
I don't have
to get away completely.
All I need is a
little distance between us!
I must say...
I'd heard you were
in bad shape...
But I never expected this.
Tag, you're it.
Utterly pathetic!
So this is the "legendary" mononoke...
Rago, the Black Star of Doom.
All right, no more talking.
You're coming with me.
You should know
we worked very hard to break
the seal that imprisoned you.
And I would prefer not
to have to kill a fellow comrade.
Comrade?
Don't make me laugh!
All you fools
care about is getting my power.
If you want it that bad,
then come and get it!
But only if you're prepared
to meet your death!
That so?
The only one meeting death is you!
K-Kid?!
You fool!
Why—?!
You're the fool, dumbass!
If you bite the dust,
then I saved you
for nothing, jerk-off!
What...?
You idiot,
you're in way over your head!
This isn't
some little street scuffle!
You really know
how to piss a guy off!
Saving someone...
...is never stupid, got it?
And when I help someone,
I help them!
I don't do it half-assed, got it?
Besides...
Even if I got away,
he'd come after me
after he got you.
You're smarter
than you look, human!
But you're a peculiar one.
My form doesn't seem to faze you
in the slightest.
And that swordsmanship,
that stealth...
Do I sense a boy of shinobi stock?
I'm gonna enjoy...
...wolfing you down!
Kid!
Th-That's...!
Utsusemi!
He's...
Oopsie!
Looks like someone
got a little too excited
with their fancy ninja moves.
Just let go.
Resisting will only make it worse.
Whoa!
That was close!
An excellent counter
from a true shinobi!
I applaud thee.
Hmm?
The darkness closing in already?
Huh?
Of course, Rago!
I'll just give him to you!
It's been a while
since your last meal, no?
I'm sure a full belly...
-will change your—
-Enough!
Shut your trap!
You're dead.
Selfish brat.
Doesn't even cross your mind that
I up and left for your benefit.
Then you ignore me when
I warned you to stay out of things.
And if you die,
all of this really will
be for nothing, you idiot.
I could eat you
and get back to my old self.
But, no, I won't.
I refuse to take orders from
that annoying halfwit demon.
That's why instead...
You're gonna eat me.
I owe you one.
And I'm gonna return the favor now.
Stop, Rago! Why you—!
What are you—?!
I take this life,
and give it to you!
Open your eyes,
Jiro!
Chief?!
It's over here as well.
Seems things have
gotten a little messy.
All hands, proceed to location!
D-Damn you, Rago!
Do you realize what you've done?!
Handing over power to
a human, a shinobi...!
You abandoned
your fellow mononoke for a human?!
Jeez, you're loud.
What's happening, crap...
Wait, what is this?!
All right, you can pick your jaw
off the floor now, kid!
Rago?!
Hey, what the hell's going on?
I'll explain later!
Watch out!
You two are living on
borrowed time!
You fused fools are mine!
Hey...
What does he mean fused?!
Priorities, kid!
We gotta kill this bastard first!
Kill him?
How do you expect me to do that?
Don't worry.
I'll give you a hand!
All you gotta do is
make a fist...
And send the piece of shit to hell!
You'll give me a hand...
Is this what you meant?
Crap...
What's going on?
Hey, tell me
what the hell's going on!
Rago?
Stay right there.
Not a word.
What the?
Who is this chick?
When did she—?!
Well, I'll be...
This is quite the pickle.
I never expected this to happen.
Shit... You're not with
that giant, are you?
Hey, no need to be rude...
We're no mononoke.
We're from the Bureau of Espionage...
Just your average civil servants.
Bureau... of Espionage?
I'll fill you in
on the details later.
As you may have already surmised,
young man,
we are taking you into custody.
Huh?!
Are you kidding me?
You can't just show up
out of nowhere and—
I told you...
Not a word.
Hey, Ichika, take it easy.
It's only temporary.
We don't want him confused
and aggressive.
Ever the dutiful agent, I must say.
So what are we
going to do with him?
For now, get 'em to our affiliate
hospital for treatment and testing.
We can't afford to
have him die on us.
He's very important.
For us...
And for the mononoke.